# NICHOLAS MCMULLEN

TALENT MANAGEMENT/HR ANALYTICS LEADER

# SUMMARY

Professional with a variety of HCM analytics, human resources, talent management, system administration, compensation administration, and statistical computing experience. Worked on multiple system implementations, including LMS and ATS. Strong desire to enter into a people operations role and contribute both analytical and people-driven efficiencies throughout the organization.

# CORE SKILLS

- Compensation administration (base & variable incentive)
- Onboarding state and federal compliance
- Change management/software system implementation
- Supervisory experience
- Talent onboarding (offer letters, pre-hire screening)
- UltiPro HRIS
- iCIMS ATS (company-wide administrator)
- R & RStudio
- Tableau Desktop
- IBM Cognos Analytics
- Cornerstone LMS (administrator experience)

# CONTACT

Mobile: (928) 951-4369

Email: nicholasgmcmullen@gmail.com Website: nickmcmullen.github.io

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/nicholas-mcmullen/

Location: Phoenix, Arizona

# EXPERIENCE

#### **BUSINESS DATA ANALYST**

#### Alliance Residential Company | Jan. 2020 - Present

- Administer variable pay incentive plan for 2000+ employees
- Administer monthly sales incentive compensation plan
- Oversee corporate executive semiannual variable pay plan
- Own all organizational data science initiatives
- Conduct statistical analyses of performance/HR/compensation data
- Work directly with C-Suite to help inform mainly people ops decisions

#### TALENT ANALYTICS MANAGER

#### Alliance Residential Company | Aug. 2018 - Jan. 2020

- Oversee Talent Coordinator team (onboarding function)
- Company-wide system administrator for ATS (iCIMS)
- Consult with top executives on base pay strategy, market job mappings
- Act as main point of contact for all vendors of Talent Management dept.
- Support organizational recruiting function

#### LEARNING MANAGER

#### Alliance Residential Company | May 2018 - August 2018

- Manage all analytics and data initiatives for training department
- System administrator for company LMS (Cornerstone)
- Assess training effectiveness and ROI (in-person & virtual)

# EDUCATION

#### **MACALESTER COLLEGE**

B.A. Applied Mathematics & Statistics, magna cum laude

August 2014 - May 2018

# CERTIFICATIONS

#### **TABLEAU SOFTWARE**

Desktop Certified Associate | Expires October 2021

#### DALE CARNEGIE TRAINING

Certified in Leading Accountable Engagement Ongoing, obtained October 2019

# ORGANIZATIONS/COMMITTEES

#### **CERTIFIED PERFORMANCE PAY COMMITTEE**

Deer Valley Unified School District | Jan. 2020 - Present

#### WORLDATWORK TOTAL REWARDS ASSOCIATION

Member | October 2019 - Present